Guide to The Billie Jean King Collection 1901-2019 (bulk, 1940-2019) MS 3147
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Albums, 1940s-2010; 19.5 Linear feet in 7 record cartons and 7 flat boxes
  - Clippings scrapbooks kept by BJK's parents (2 albums), 1968-1974 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7B)
    Two scrapbooks created by BJK's parents, Bill and Betty Moffitt, containing newspaper clippings documenting BJK's career. Subjects of clippings include the Battle of the Sexes match against Bobby Riggs, general profiles of BJK, Women's Indoor Tennis Championships, and the founding and first season of the World TeamTennis league and the Philadelphia Freedoms team.
  - Battle of the Sexes (2 of 4 albums), 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7C)
    Albums containing newspaper clippings, letters, and scattered ephemera related to the Battle of the Sexes match between BJK and Bobby Riggs.
  - Battle of the Sexes (2 of 4 albums), 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8A)
  - World TeamTennis Hawaii Leis clippings, 1974 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8B)
    Album containing newspaper clippings of coverage of the World TeamTennis Hawaii Leis matches and players.
  - Kansas City clippings, 1975-1978 (Offsite-box 15, Volume 2)
    Album containing newspaper clippings on BJK primarily from the Kansas City Star, covering topics including Battle of the Sexes, Wimbledon, World TeamTennis, and BJK's tennis career in general.
  - World TeamTennis clippings, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13A)
    Album containing newspaper clippings and several magazines with coverage of World TeamTennis.
  - WTT New York Sets clippings, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 2)
    Contains clippings covering the World TeamTennis franchise New York Sets, particularly BJK's arrival for the 1975 season. Album arrived disbound.
  - June Harrison published photography, 1975-2000 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
    Album containing color photocopies of June Harrison's tennis photography as published in various publications, including Tennis magazine, The Telegraph, The News World, and WomenSports. Also includes copies of photos and slides, many of World TeamTennis matches with Billie Jean King.
  - Porsche Tennis Grand Prix tournament, 1979 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8C)
    Scrapbook containing photographs of BJK competing in the Porsche Tennis Grand Prix 1979.
  - Avon Championships of Chicago (2 albums), 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 9)
    Two scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings, promotional material, and event material for the 1979 and 1980 Avon Championships of Chicago.
  - NBC Wimbledon, 1981 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 1)
    Album containing photographs, clippings, and program from Wimbledon 1981 prepared for BJK by NBC Television Network.
  - Chicago Tennis newsclippings, 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 11, Volume 1)
    Scrapbook containing newspaper clippings generally covering Women's Tennis news published in Chicago papers.
  - World TeamTennis Dallas Stars, 1982 (Offsite-box 11, Volume 2)
    Scrapbook containing promotional material, correspondence, and newspaper clippings related to the Dallas Stars World TeamTennis team.
  - 1983 Virginia Slims Chicago Tribune (Offsite-box 8, Box 8D)
    Scrapbook containing newspaper clippings on the Virignia Slims Championship published in the Chicago Tribune.
  - Virginia Slims of Chicago Tournament Week Publicity, 1983 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 2)
    Scrapbook containing newspaper clippings and photocopies of clippings covering the Virginia Slims of Chicago Tournament Week 1983.
  - Photo album, 1983-2002 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
    Photo album including shots of BJK at Wimbledon 1983, 2002 photos of BJK with Senator Hillary Clinton and Julie Foudy for National Girls and Women in Sports Day.
  - Los Angeles Olympics album, 1984 (Offsite-box 67, Folder 5)
  - Bill and Mildred "Betty" Moffitt Golden Anniversary, 1991 May 17 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
    Album with photographs, cards, and party guest inscriptions from Golden Wedding Anniversary celebration of BJK's parents, Bill and Betty Moffitt.
  - Virginia Slims Legends, circa 1994 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
    Contains photos from the Virgina Slims Legends tour matches and off-court activities. Players include Tracy Austin, Chris Evert, Billie Jean King, Ilana Kloss, Martina Navratilova, and Virginia Wade.
  - Fed Cup USA vs The Netherlands, 1998 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
    Album containing photos of the 1998 United States Fed Cup team's matches, captained by BJK.
  - BJK and Sri Chimnoy photo album, circa 2000-2007 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
    Album of photos of Billie Jean King and Sri Chinmoy, spiritual leader and founder of the World Harmony Run.
  - USTA album, 2001 October (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
    Album presented to BJK containing photos of various USTA events, some including BJK.
  - World TeamTennis at St. Louis photo album, 2001 (Offsite-box 44, Box 44A)
    Album created by Marianne Dillow.
  - Marianne Dillow World TeamTennis scrapbook, 2002 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12A)
    Scrapbook created by Marianne Dillow and containing photographs, original drawings, and captions of BJK and Ilana Kloss' professional activities of 2002, primarily documenting various World TeamTennis teams and events.
  - World TeamTennis Smash Hits Philadelphia, 2002 (Offsite-box 44, Box 44B)
  - Marianne Dillow World TeamTennis scrapbook, 2003 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12B)
    Scrapbook created by Marianne Dillow and containing photographs, original drawings, and captions of BJK and Ilana Kloss' professional activitities of 2003, primarily documenting various World TeamTennis teams and events.
  - Altria Invitational at PGA National Palm Beach Gardens, Florida, 2003 February 16 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
    Two albums containing photos from the Altria Invitational tennis tournament held at PGA National Resort, Palm Beach Gardens, Florida. Players include Tracy Austin, BJK, Chris Evert, Ilana Kloss, and Virginia Wade.
  - ITF World Champions Dinner: Honouring 40 Years of Fed Cup, 2003 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 9)
    Album sent to BJK from the International Tennis Federation containing photographs from the IFT World Champions Dinner 2003.
  - BJK 60th Birthday (2 folders), 2003 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 10-11)
    Contains digital photo files on CD and printed thumbnails of photos from BJK's 60th birthday party in Los Angeles and an album presented to BJK by Women's Sports Foundation staff.
    Conditions Governing Access
    CD is restricted from access in order to ensure the digital files are not accidentally corrupted. N-YHS will be developing procedures to properly handle digital media and this content will be opened in the future after those procedures are established and implemented.
  - New York City bid for Summer Olympics 2012, 2005 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12C)
    Binder containing the participant guide for members of the Evaluation Committee for New York City's bid proposal as Candidate City for the 2012 Summer Olympics. BJK participated in the presentations to the IOC. Contents include documents with background information on NYC's bid, bios of members of the Committee, the event schedule for the Evaluation Commission, presentation guidelines, and an insert of related newspaper clippings.
  - Advanta Women's Sports Foundation event, 2005 September 7 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 12)
    Album of photos from Advanta Women's Sports Foundation fundraising event, including photos of BJK with Elton John.
  - US Open Opening Ceremonies, 2006 August 28 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 13)
    Photo album from the US Open Opening Ceremonies and naming of the USTA Billie Jean King National Tennis Center. Photos taken by photographer for Mayor Michael Bloomberg. Image permissions owned by the Municipal Archives of New York, Mayor Michael Bloomberg Photograph Collection.
  - BJK USTA National Tennis Center, 2006 August 28 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13B)
    Scrapbook album including photos from the ceremony for the naming of the BJK USTA National Tennis Center.
  - Marianne Dillow World TeamTennis scrapbook, 2006 (Offsite-box 44, Box 44C)
  - California Governor and First Lady's Conference on Women, 2010 (Offsite-box 6, Volume 3)
    Album containing pages of images from the California Governor and First Lady's Conference on Women 2010. Images show various events, honorees, and attendees, including BJK.
- Series III. Subject files, 1950s-2018; 5 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
  Series III contains subject files collected and maintained by BJK in the course of her tennis career and beyond. Subjects include individuals, organizations and institutions, and general office files created by BJK. Material types include handwritten notes, event files and programs, and daily schedules. The subject files reflect BJK's wide-ranging involvement with advocacy organizations and causes in addition to her commitment to tennis and the TeamTennis league. Material dates from the 1950s to 2018.
  Arranged in five subseries:
  Subseries III.A. General subject files
  Subseries III.B. Tennis career
  Subseries III.C. Elton John AIDS Foundation
  Subseries III.D. Film Projects
  Subseries III.E. World TeamTennis
  - Subseries III.A. General subject files, 1950s-2018; 3 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    Subseries III.A contains general office files, files kept by BJK on individual colleagues and public figures, and files on particular organizations and institutions. General files include BJK's address books, daily calendars, and letterhead. Notable individuals with a personal subject file include Hillary Clinton, tennis player Althea Gibson, Elton John, Charles Schulz, and BJK's first tennis coach Clyde Walker. Subject files on particular organizations include event programs and notes. Notable organizations with a subject file include the BJK Leadership Initiative, founded in 2014 by BJK and Ilana Kloss, the Women's Sports Foundation, founded by BJK in 1974, and the Women's Tennis Association, formed by BJK in 1973. Material dates from the 1950s-2018.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Address books (3 folders), circa 1990s-2000s (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1-3)
    - Althea Gibson, 1974-2017 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 4)
    - Annalee Marie Thurston, 2007 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5)
    - Basketball, circa 1970s (Offsite-box 16, Folder 6)
    - Billie Jean King Foundation (4 folders), 1999-2000s (Offsite-box 16, Folder 7-10)
    - Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative, 2018 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 11)
    - Bud Collins, 2016 (Offsite-box 67, Folder 7)
    - Calendar (5 folders), 1978, 2006-2010 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 12-16)
    - California State University, 1964 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 17)
    - Cartoons, 1970s-2000s (Offsite-box 16, Folder 18)
    - Charles M. Schulz, 2000-2012 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 19)
    - Clyde Walker, circa 1950s-1961 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 20)
    - Contacts and business cards, circa 2000s (Offsite-box 16, Folder 21)
    - Elton John, 2007 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 22)
      Contains sheet music for Philadelphia Freedom signed by Elton John and Bernie Taupin for Billie Jean King and invitation and setlist for Elton John's 60th birthday celebration concert at Madison Square Garden on March 25, 2007.
    - Events (5 of 8 folders), 1975-2008 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 23-27)
    - Events (3 of 8 folders), 2009-2019 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1-3)
    - Health, 2010 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
    - Hillary Clinton, 2007-2019 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
    - International Tennis Hall of Fame, 2007 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
    - Languages, circa 2000s (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
    - Latin American International Sports Hall of Fame, 2007-2008 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
    - Lee Holley, 2000s (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
      Contains material related to American cartoonist and comic artist Lee Holley.
    - Letterhead, circa 1980s-1990s (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
    - LGBTQ advocacy organizations, 2006-2018 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 11)
    - Los Angeles Dodgers, 2018-2019 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 12)
    - National Jewish Sports Hall of Fame and Museum (2 folders), 2005-2006 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 13-14)
    - National Women's Hall of Fame, 1999 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 15)
    - New-York Historical Society (1 of 2 folders), 2018-2019 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 16)
    - New-York Historical Society (2 of 2 folders), 2019 November 12 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 12)
      Contains BJK handwritten notes for BJK at 75 event and note from performer to BJK.
    - Notebook, circa 1965 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 17)
    - Presidential Inauguration, 2013 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 18)
    - Presidential Medal of Freedom, 2006-2009 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 19)
    - President's Council on Fitness, Sports, and Nutrition (2 folders), 2011-2014 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 20-21)
    - Pressure is a Privilege, 2008 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 22)
    - The Renfrew Center, 2007-2008 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 23)
    - Sochi Olympics, 2014 (Offsite-box 17, Box 24)
    - Terry Castle, 2004-2007 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 24)
    - Title IX (2 folders), 2002-2007 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 25-26)
    - US Open, 1976-2012 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 28)
    - USTA [United States Tennis Association] (2 folders), 1977-2018 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 29-30)
    - Wimbledon (4 of 17 folders), 1981-2006 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 31-34)
      Contains official souvenir programs, invitations, menus, Royal Box tickets and seating charts, and Wimbledon publications. Each year's file may contain a variety of these document types.
    - Wimbledon (13 of 17 folders), 2007-2019 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1-13)
      Contains official souvenir programs, invitations, menus, Royal Box tickets and seating charts, and Wimbledon publications. Each year's file may contain a variety of these document types. The 2018 file includes BJK's schedule itinerary with handwritten notes.
    - Women's advocacy organizations, 2006-2018 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 14)
    - Women's Sports Foundation (8 folders), 2006-2018 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 15-22)
      Contains materials related to the Women's Sports Foundation, an organization started by BJK in 1974 to advance the lives of women and girls through greater access to sports and physical activity and to protect the sports provisions of Title IX. Documents include publicity material, programs for the Annual Salute to Women in Sports and The Billies events, Board of Trustees meeting agendas, handbooks, and reports, and "History of the Beginnings and Leadership of the WSF" document.
    - Women's Tennis Association (3 folders), 2003-2014 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1-3)
      Contains materials related to the Women's Tennis Association, formed by BJK in 1973 as the principal organizing body of women's professional tennis.
    - World Harmony Run, 2008 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 4)
    - Youth advocacy organizations, 2007 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 5)
  - Subseries III.B. Tennis career, 1956-2000; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Subseries III.B contains files spanning BJK's tennis career, including tournament play, the Battle of the Sexes match against Bobby Riggs, and the evolution of women's professional tennis, including the Virginia Slims Circuit. Materials include Grand Slam tournament results, event programs, tournament brackets, and endorsement advertisements. Material dates from 1959-2000.
    - Pacific Southwest Tennis Championships, 1956-1961 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 6)
      Contains programs from 1956 and 1961 for the Pacific Southwest Tennis Championships held at the Los Angeles Tennis Club. Billie Jean Moffitt listed in the 1956 Girls' Singles (13 Years) bracket and the 1961 Junior Girls' Singles and Junior Girls' Doubles brackets.
    - BJK career draw sheets, 1958-1983 (Offsite-box 67, Folder 6)
      Contains printed draw sheets for BJK's matches at the U.S. Nationals singles, doubles, and mixed doubles matches from 1958-1967, U.S. Open (after name change) from 1968-1983, and Australian Open from 1965-1983.
    - Wightman Cup, 1959-1964 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7)
      Contains documents related to the Wightman Cup, an annual women's tennis match between British and American teams. Items include a 1959 certificate of participation, 1961 telegram from Wightman Cup captain Margaret duPont, 1964 program, and 1965 letter and enclosed team photograph from Margaret duPont.
    - United States Lawn Tennis Association, 1960-1975 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 8)
      Contains a range of match programs, brackets, photographs, and correspondence from United States Lawn Tennis Association competitions (USLTA).
    - Federation Cup, 1963-1976 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9)
      Contains newspaper clippings, programs, and score reports from the Federation Cup, the premier international team competition in women's tennis.
    - Tulsa Tennis Club, 1966 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 10)
      Contains program for the Tulsa Tennis Club's Ninth Annual Invitation Tennis Tournament.
    - Lawn Tennis Association, 1967 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 11)
      Contains program and seating chart for The Lawn Tennis Association Ball.
    - National Tennis League, 1968 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 12)
      Contains program from National Tennis League presents Professional Tennis at the New Inglewood Forum 1968.
    - Endorsements (2 folders), 1968-2000s (Offsite-box 19, Folder 13-14)
      Contains advertisements featuring BJK, including American Express, Aztec suntan lotion, Colgate, Geico, In-Dink-Erator Disposers, Nutrisystem, as well as a license agreement wih Head & Ski Sports Wear, Inc. and materials from the Adidas Here to Create Change campaign.
    - Virginia Slims Circuit (3 folders), 1970-1983 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 15-17)
      Contains correspondence, ephemera, player bios, press releases, and tournament programs and brackets related to the Virginia Slims Circuit.
    - Maureen Connolly Brinker International Ladies Tennis Championship, 1972 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 18)
      Contains tournament bracket.
    - Battle of the Sexes (2 folders), 1973 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 19-20)
      Contains copies of programs and page of cheers for the Battle of the Sexes match between BJK and Bobby Riggs.
    - Battle of the Sexes 25th Anniversary (2 folders), 1998 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 21-22)
      Contains copies of letters sent to BJK by fans following the Battle of the Sexes match, organized and prepared for BJK by the Women's Sports Foundation in celebration of the 25th anniversary of the match.
    - Virginia Slims Legends Tour, 1998 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 23)
      Contains programs for The Virgina Slims Legends Tour April 26-27, 1997 in Chicago and October 17-18, 1998 in The Woodlands, Texas. Both program covers have signatures from the tournament players including Tracy Austin, Rosie Casals, Chris Evert, Zina Garrison Jackson, Evonne Goolagong, Billie Jean King, Martina Navratilova, Pam Shriver, Wendy Turnbull, and Virginia Wade.
  - Subseries III.C. Elton John AIDS Foundation, 2000-2018; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Subseries III.C contains all files related to BJK's work with the Elton John AIDS Foundation and is comprised of mostly event files and programs. Materials date from 2000-2018.
    - Events and fundraising files (10 folders), 2000-2018 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 24-33)
  - Subseries III.D. Film projects, 1997-2018; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Subseries III.D contains files generated by and related to various film projects BJK has been involved with, including documentaries, feature films, and as a guest on several television shows. Material types include call sheets, newspaper and magazine clippings, correspondence, press kits, and scripts. Materials date from 1997-2018.
    - The David Letterman Show, 1997 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
    - Thunderbird Productions, 1997 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
    - Dare to Compete: The Struggle of Women in Sports, 1999 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
    - When Billie Beat Bobby (6 folders), 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4-9)
    - A Hero for Daisy, 2001 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 10)
    - The L Word, 2005 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 11)
    - Billie Jean King: Portrait of a Pioneer (3 folders), 2006 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 12-14)
    - Law & Order, 2007 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 15)
    - Fresh Off the Boat script, 2015 October 22 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 5)
    - Battle of the Sexes, 2016-2018 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 16)
  - Subseries III.E. World TeamTennis, 1974-2017; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Subseries III.E contains files related to World TeamTennis, the mixed-gender professional tennis league founded in 1973. Materials include event files and schedules for the league and for particular teams, roster documents, press releases, and administrative information. Material dates from the first TeamTennis season in 1974 to 2017.
    - General file, 1975-1983 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 17)
      Includes documents and publications related to the entire WTT league, such as scheduling and roster information, publicity files, and ephemera.
    - 30th reunion, 2005 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 18)
    - Boston Lobsters, 1974-2008 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 19)
    - Commercial building and retrofit, inc., circa 2000 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 20)
    - Delaware Smash, 2005 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 21)
    - Draft, 2017 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 22)
    - Folders, circa 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 67, Folder 8)
      Contains two white folders printed with World TeamTennis and TeamTennis designs.
    - Golden Gators, 1977 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 23)
    - Hawaii Leis, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 24)
    - The History of World TeamTennis, 2017 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 25)
    - Houston Wranglers, 2005 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 26)
    - Junior Nationals, 2012-2018 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 27)
    - Media Guides, 1974-1975, 2018 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 28)
    - New York Apples (4 folders), 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 29-32)
    - New York Empire, 2016-2017 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 33)
    - New York Sportimes, 2005 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 34)
    - Philadelphia Freedoms (2 folders), 1974-2013 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 35-36)
    - Press releases (2 folders), 1981-1984 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Professional League materials (3 folders), 1989-1991 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3-5)
    - San Antonio Racquets, circa 2000s (Offsite-box 21, Folder 6)
    - San Diego Buds, 1985 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 7)
    - Seattle Cascades, 1978 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 8)
    - Smash Hits (3 folders), 2002-2008 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 9-11)
    - St. Louis Aces, 2005 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 12)
    - Stationery, 2000s (Offsite-box 21, Folder 13)
- Series IV. Speeches, 2002-2019; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Series IV includes speech files from BJK's speaking engagements and appearances at various corporate, political, and non-profit organizations. Types of material throughout the speech files include BJK's typed and handwritten notes prepared for her remarks, itineraries and schedules for events, service agreements, and correspondence. Topics of BJK's speeches often include personal and professional anecdotes, leadership and mentorship, women's sports, and women's rights initiatives.
  - International Working Group conference, 2002 May 18 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 14)
    Contains typed remarks with handwritten edits for the International Working Group conference held in Montreal. Topics of speech include leadership, activism, pursuing social change, the history of Women's Tennis Association, and earning inequalities in sports.
  - WISE [Women in Sports and Events] luncheon, 2002 June 3 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 15)
    Contains typed speech for the WISE luncheon, with remarks on leadership and addressing under-represented populations, particularly women of color, in the sports industry.
  - Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study, 2002 June 7 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 16)